# 打个滚 多漂亮
Roll it, beautiful!
# 山楂小红果
They are like hawthorns,
# 小红酱豆腐
or red fermented bean curds.
# 亮晶晶 漂亮
So shiny and beautiful.
# 红菜头
Beetroots,
# 铁棍山药
Chinese Yam.
# 这是红菜头切之前的样子
This is what beetroot looks like before you cut it.
# 我们以为什么呢 咸菜疙瘩
We thought it was a lump of pickled vegetable or somthing.
# 这一切开马上就变了色了
But, as soon as you cut it open, it changes color.
# 不一样了 看看
Looks, it's different.
# 天然色素
This is natural food coloring.
# 把脏的皮只要洗干净可以了
We have to clean the dirty skins.
# 煮上就行
And then, boil the beetroots.
# 煮多长时间
For how long?
# 今天您看 就已经煮了三十分钟了
Today we have already boiled for 30min.
# 煮这个你主要是看这颜色行就行
It mainly depends on its color.
# 一定是选铁棍山药 是面的
We have to choose iron stick yam, because it is very mushy inside.
# 含淀粉量高一点
Because it contains high level of starch,
# 就需要要它里边的绵
it is very mushy and smooth inside.
# 就含淀粉量比较高
Has lots of starch.
# 淀粉加热就变成有黏度的 没错
Yes, and after you heat it up, the starch becomes sticky.
# 这我削完皮以后就蒸
I will steam them after peeling off the skins.
# 这就是咱们蒸好的
Those have already been steamed.
# 提前蒸好的 二十分钟
We steam them for about 20min.
# 二十分钟 蒸透蒸黏
Yea, 20min will thoroughly cook them.
# 菜墩有一个红点 那是染的
Our cutting board has a little red dot on it. This came from the beetroot.
# 所以说网友朋友们
So,
# 咱们切红菜头
If you want to cut beetroot,
# 尽量底下垫一个毛巾垫一个布
we recommend putting a towel between it and the cutting board.
# 省的把菜墩子染了
So that the beetroot won't dye our cutting board.
# 它是天然色素
It is natural food coloring.
# 我慢慢干着 有樱桃
I'm not in a rush. Here are the cherries.
# 把把儿给我留着 把儿别给我扔了
Don't throw away the handles on the cherries please.
# 一定要趁热
We have to mash the yams while they are still hot.
# 凉了之后淀粉它就自动凝固了
Because the starch will solidify after it cools down.
# 凝固了它就不能用
Then, we cannot use it anymore.
# 这是一甜口菜
We are making a dessert
# 铁棍山药本身它就含糖
Since Chinese yam contains sugar itself,
# 吃的是有微甜的感觉
it actually tastes a little sweet.
# 不用再加糖
So, we don't have to add any extra sugar.
# 愿意吃甜口更重一点的
But if you like sweet food,
# 加点糖没问题
you certainly can add more sugar at your own preference.
# 蜂蜜也可以 但是适量
Honey works as well, but we cannot add too much.
# 一定不能影响它的凝结
Otherwise it will solidify the yams.
# 其实还是那句话 一通百通
In general, if you can master one thing, you can as well master other things.
# 你可以做臭豆腐吗
Can you make Chinese Stinky Tofu from this yam?
# 我给你熬一灰色的
I will make you a gray-color sauce.
# 您看刚才您吃完那把儿
You see the little handle from the cherry.
# 我得先给它整一下型
I will make a shape first.
# 使手捏一下
Sqeeze with my fingers.
# 隋师傅做活就是干净
Master Sui is so clean.
# 永远戴手套
Always wearing gloves.
# 弄个眼
We poke a little hole on it.
# 好看
Nice!
# 然后就跟它一比这不就爷俩了吗
Compare to a cherry, it is like grandfather and grandson.
# 一会儿挂完颜色再看看
We will see later after coloring it.
# 下边铺一张锡纸或者保鲜膜
We can pave a layer of plastic or aluminum foil on the bottom.
# 取的时候好取 方便
So that it is easier to take the yams off.
# 靠到一边
Set this aside.
# 然后用手给它加工到
And then use our hands
# 和腐乳厚度相似 差不多
to shape it into the thinkness of a fermented bean curd chunk.
# 如果没有这个 您家里边有什么
If you don't have this kind of metal box,
# 这种带楞带角的方形的
you can use any square shaped containers.
# 比如饭盒 一次性餐盒都可以
Like lunch box, or throw-away lunchbox.
# 给它拍平了之后
After we make this flat,
# 要放冰箱给它（冷藏）一下
we need to freeze it
# 进冰箱怎么着最短也得十五分钟
for at least 15min.
# 冷却透 让它淀粉凝固了就可以了
We have to completely solidify the starch inside the yams.
# 不耽误大家时间
We won't waste your time.
# 我提前冻好了一块
I have already frozen one.
# 真有心眼子
So smart!
# 跟大白油似的 多好看
Like white fat, beautiful.
# 这山药 白如羊脂
This yam is as white as mutton fat.
# 根据大约腐乳的大小
We will make it the size of a fermented bean curd chunk.
# 三叔咱们就做六块吧
San Shu, let's make six pieces.
# 我觉得够咱俩吃一块就行了
I feel like one piece is enough for us.
# 我闻闻味 这味还小
Let me smell it. There aren't too much smell on it.
# 这六块够了
Six pieces are enough.
# 然后咱们把汁要给它过滤出来
Then, we have to strain out the beetroot sauce.
# 熬的差不多了 够黏够稠 颜色够重
This is good, both the stickiness and the color.
# 过下箩
Over the strainer.
# 糖一勺就行 微微小甜
We will add only a spoon of sugar for a slight sweetness.
# 鱼胶粉也搁一小勺 差不多
And a spoon of gelatin.
# 再来一点也行
Maybe a little more.
# 这把它搅匀之后
After mixing it thoroughly,
# 得让它冷却到四十度左右
we have to cool it down to around 40 degree Celcius.
# 它已经粘稠了再往上挂
We have to wait until the sauce is sticky enough.
# 热着挂不上
Otherwise it won't sticky to the yam.
# 得 这汁冷却得了
It should be good right now.
# 然后咱们测一下基本温度
Let's measure the temperature.
# 高科技仪器 二十九点一 可以
Technology I have! 29.9 Celcius, good.
# 咱们看基本的状态
Let's feel it.
# 粘稠的 可以了
Sticky, it is good.
# 咱们这菜说话就完了
This is dish is compelte while we are chatting.
# 蘸一下 打个滚
Dip it in, and roll it.
# 天然色素 多漂亮
Natural coloring, so beautiful.
# 山楂小红果
They are like like hawthorns.
# 然后把它放在这个上面 冷却
Then, we cool it down.
# 你看底下搁菠萝
See, there is a piece of pineapple on the bottom.
# 咱们家里搁一面团也行
You can use a dough as well.
# 一遍不行可以蘸两遍
We can also dip it twice.
# 漂亮漂亮
So nice.
# 放凉一下
Let it cool.
# 小红酱豆腐
They are like red fermented bean curds.
# 这是最后一遍 蘸了三遍
I have dipped this three times.
# 带腐乳汤
It even has a little bit extra sauce.
# 亮晶晶
Shiny.
# 齐活 干净利落 漂亮
Clean and beautiful.
# 来啦
There we go.
# 吃块酱豆腐 腐乳这么费劲呐
Why does it take so long to eat "fermented bean curds"
# 来了 说来就来了
Here we go.
# 你看看隋大师做了一个小腐乳
See, Master Sui has just made some "fermented bean curds".
# 创意性的 给家带点儿乐 红红火火
This is an innovative dish which will bring you happiness.
# 来一腐乳
Let me try one.
# 这个甜度合适
The sweetness is just right.
# 小焦 下手
Jiao, use your hand.
# 我吃这个吧
I will try this one.
# 红果这个面啊
It's so mushy and smooth.
# 这小菜做的
What a dish!
# import ending.srt 00:05:00,000